秋风萧萧绕古城
Autumn wind whistles 'round the ancient town
茶馆巷陌 说书的人
In teahouses and lanes, the storyteller sits
街角掩庭院深深
Deep courtyards hide 'neath street corners
藏燕青门里几度春秋
Within Yanqing Gate, years come and go
雨打磨剑痕
Rain polishes the sword's scars
武医心法贯乾坤
Martial and medical wisdom run through heaven and earth
他抛洒的热血仍残留温存
The blood he shed still holds a trace of warmth
曾有故事中的他
Once there was him in tales
义薄云天 风姿潇洒
Righteous above all, graceful and unrestrained
燕青引箭生繁花
Yanqing draws the bow, and flowers bloom
扶危救困名震天下
Aiding the needy, his fame resounds across the land
何以为侠
What is chivalry?
耳畔风声无涯
The wind whispers endlessly by the ear
可寻得真英雄的回答
Can we find the answer of a true hero?
燕青门前十载春夏
Ten springs and autumns before Yanqing Gate
武医天术纵横天下
Martial and medical arts prevail across the land
为天地 为苍生 为国为家
For heaven and earth, for all living beings, for country and home
我愿用我弹指剑花
I'd gladly use the sword flowers from my flick of the wrist
挽出一个盛世繁华
To weave a prosperous age of glory
再许你白首韶华
And vow to share with you the years till white hair comes
啊 啊 啊
Ah, ah, ah
星河欲转夜未休
Stars are about to shift, the night lingers on
山河浩浩 天地悠悠
Rivers and mountains stretch vast, heaven and earth are boundless
潮水自翻腾不休
The tide surges and rolls without cease
似燕青门里侠义千秋
Like the eternal chivalry within Yanqing Gate
风云几度
Through countless winds and clouds
多少英雄风流
How many heroes lived in glory
史册间 一抹英魂不朽
Between history's pages, a heroic soul remains eternal
燕青门前十载春夏
Ten springs and autumns before Yanqing Gate
武医天术纵横天下
Martial and medical arts prevail across the land
为天地 为苍生 为国为家
For heaven and earth, for all living beings, for country and home
我愿用我弹指剑花
I'd gladly use the sword flowers from my flick of the wrist
挽出一个盛世繁华
To weave a prosperous age of glory
再许你白首韶华
And vow to share with you the years till white hair comes
如今你我盛世为家
Now we have this prosperous age as our home
不见昔日金戈铁马
No longer seeing the old days of swords and armor
名与利 功与禄 何足记挂
Fame and fortune, merits and ranks—what's there to care for?
抛却俗世扰扰纷杂
Cast aside the chaos and noise of the mortal world
明朝打马 仗剑天涯
Tomorrow we ride horses, wield swords across the land
共并肩 逐梦天下
Side by side, chasing dreams across the land